Maurice Hindus Papers
Maurice Hindus Papers
1938-1967
Hindus, Maurice Gerschon, 1891-1969.
2.75 linear ft.
Papers of the novelist, author, and American authority on the Soviet Union. Collection includes manuscripts and/or production records for books on the Soviet Union, including The Cossacks (1945), Crisis in the Kremlin (1954), House Without a Roof (1961), and The Kremlin's Human Dilemma (1967), as well as for the novel Magda (1951) and the autobiographical Green Worlds (1938).
149397
Biographical History
Maurice Hindus (1891-1969) was a Russian-born novelist and American authority on the Soviet Union. He was the author of several books on peasant life in Russia as well as his own autobiography, Green Worlds (1938).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Maurice Hindus Papers consists entirely of his writings, specifically material relating to his books. Titles represented in the collection are The Cossacks (1945), Crisis in the Kremlin (1954), House Without a Roof (1961), and The Kremlin's Human Dilemma (1967), as well as for the novel Magda (1951) and the autobiographical Green Worlds (1938).. The collection includes manuscripts, production records, galley proofs, and other formats.
Arrangement of the Collection
Material is arranged alphabetically by title.
Subject and Genre Headings
Literature -- American Fiction; Radicalism; Hindus, Maurice Gerschon, 1891-1969.; Authors -- United States.; Novelists -- United States.; Soviet Union -- Civilization.; Soviet Union -- Description and travel.; Soviet Union -- Foreign relations -- 1945-1991.; Galley proofs.; Manuscripts for publication.; Authors.; Novelists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Unpublished guide.
Inventory
- Writings (books)
  - The Cossacks, 1945; manuscript; 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Crisis in the Kremlin, 1954
    - Manuscript, 8 folders (Box 1)
    - Production records, galley proofs; 8 folders (Box 1)
  - Green Worlds, 1938; manuscript; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - House Without a Roof, 1961
    - Manuscripts, 6 folders (Box 1)
    - Manuscripts, 8 folders (Box 2)
    - Production records, galley proofs; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - The Kremlin's Human Dilemma, 1967
    - Manuscript, 8 folders (Box 2)
    - Production records, galley proofs; 3 folders (Box 2)
    - Production records, galley proofs; 2 folders (Box 3)
  - Magda, 1951
    - Manuscripts, 6 folders (Box 3)
    - Production records, galley proofs; 2 folders (Box 4)